Joel Stoddard 6825 Errick Rd North Tonawanda, NY 14120 716-208-4953 Joel9818@hotmail.com

Career Overview

Committed and motivated professional with exceptional customer-relation, and decision-making skills. Strong work ethic, professional demeanor and great initiative.

Excellent communication and computer skills; analytical skills; and the ability to work independently or as part of a team to meet project deadlines; multicultural awareness with a high level of adaptability with operational experience and business process and procedure understanding.

Objective:

 To secure a position with your company utilizing my skills and experience Associate of Arts in Information Technology Services and/or other related job Customer Service.

Summary of Qualifications:

- Over ten years of customer service experience in several settings including retail, call center, medical insurance and banking.
- Committed to building expertise in web communications, social media, and search engine marketing through exceptional work ethic and ability to quickly absorb and apply new information.
- Experience using windows, Microsoft Office, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, and EBay

Education and Achievements:

University of Phoenix Oct 2010 – Jan 2014

Associates Degree – Associate of Arts in Information Technology Services

- Desktop support, network support, multimedia development, information security, database administration, web administration.
- Knowledge and skills in Information Technology professional competence and values, information utilization, collaboration, communication, medical terminology, critical thinking and problem solving.

Professional Experience:

Holebrook Heating and Cooling

Lead Generation June 2018- Present

- Approach customers within Home Depot stores to spark interest in setting appointment for our heating and cooling sales representative
- Knowledge and understanding of the different systems offered
- Set appointments via phone, fax, paper copy and chat
- Assist cleints with further needs
- Focus on the needs of the client
- Interact with store associates on a daily basis and develop good repore with associates and store manager.

First Niagara Bank-Key Bank – Lockport, NY Customer Service Representative

Apr 2016 - Apr 2018

- Handled inbound service calls from clients answering inquiries, resolving issues and responding to client needs and concerns.
- Always focus on delivering a great client experience without the pressure of sales quotas

- Interact with other internal Key Bank departments and third parties such as dealerships and other financial institutions complete payoffs.
- Assisted clients with online banking difficulties and problem shoot their technical concerns.

Kelley Services-M&T Bank - Williamsville, NY **Online Customer Service Technical Specialist**

Jan 2016 - Mar 2016

- Perform all tasks related to the enrollment and operational maintenance of Web Banking.
- Troubleshoots issues in order to determine root cause of customer problems.
- Maneuvers through internal and external applications relating to Web Banking (i.e. CSW/ CIS, Relationship Manager and Intelligent Authentication Tool.)
- Correctly and legibly complete all forms, electronic and paper, required to complete customer requests.

AAA - Williamsville, NY

Oct 2015 - Dec 2015

Membership Representative

- Provide telephone service to incoming callers regarding all club operations
- Ability to multi-task and to prioritize work effectively
- Take payment information via telephone

Sykes Enterprises – Amherst, NY

Dec 2014 - Oct 2015

Mortgage Specialist

- Provide expert mortgage information to Wells Fargo Mortgage holders via telephone
- Provide expert customer service via telephone
- Take payment information via telephone
- Offer products and services to customers

Aroma Restaurant Amherst, NY

Aug 2014 - Sep 2014

Porter

- Performed daily restaurant duties to prepare for service
- Checked incoming inventory deliveries to orders

Juicy Vapor - Amherst, NY

Dec 2012 - Jul 2014

Sales Representatives

- Performed daily retail store opening and closing procedures
- Selling of Electronic Devices and helping customers use them.

Main Street Host - Amherst, NY

Feb 2006 - Jun 2011

Review Specialist

- Provided daily updates for our clients when needed to better rank them on Google, Yahoo, and Bing. Maintain website content for many of our clients along with review of how they ranked.
- Created links resources page and added new links to help the client.
- Updated client's websites on Yahoo, Homestead, and Google.

Blue Wireless - North Tonawanda, NY

Sep 2008 - Jul 2009

Sales Representatives

- Provided cell phone technology retail sales support and customer service at multiple store locations
- Performed daily retail store opening and closing procedures
- Troubleshoot problems relating to handset performance
- Processed bill payments and maintained all in-store trackers

Zstar Satellite - Blasdell, NY

Mar 2005 - Feb 2008

Sales Consultants

- Provided satellite dish information to assist customers with consumer decision making.
- Sold Dish Network, DirecTV and Hughes net satellite technology services.

Updated customer's orders and business database.

Auto Trader – Lancaster, NY Advertising Consultant

Sep 2007 - Jan 2008

- Advertising Consultant of the month for top sales in the month (January 2008)
- Generated and expanded relationships with assigned dealer partners and prospects to maximize revenue opportunities
- Reviewed advertising options with customers and provided recommendations
- Consulted with dealer partners to determine their business needs and offer the best utilization of the products and services offered

Teletech, Niagara Falls, NY Customer Service Representative

Mar 2003 - Aug 2007

- Worked on various projects ranging from Verizon Wireless, United Health Care Medicare Part D, Government Program
- · Resolved customer inquiries until issue is resolved and in a timely manner
- Answered inbound calls from customers Verizon Wireless to service existing wireless communication accounts, billing, troubleshooting connectivity problems, and sold upgrades to latest technology phones.
- Research of complex cases and concerns through varies avenues available